Joseph Holt Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Joseph Holt Papers 1797-1917 (bulk 1859-1889)
MSS26385
Holt, Joseph, 1807-1894
20,000 items
118 containers and 3 oversize
26.2 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
United States Postmaster general, secretary of war, judge advocate general of the United States Army, and lawyer. Correspondence, diaries, financial papers, legal papers, newspaper clippings, speeches, photographs, and printed matter relating to Holt's duties as judge advocate general, especially his work on the military commission that tried the Lincoln assassination conspirators, the trial of Mary Surratt, and various controversies surrounding the work of the commission. Other topics include Kentucky and Mississippi politics, Democratic Party politics, the elections of 1852 and 1856, the Civil War, and Holt's duties as secretary of war.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Black, Jeremiah S. (Jeremiah Sullivan), 1810-1883--Correspondence.; Buchanan, James, 1791-1868--Correspondence.; Cameron, Simon, 1799-1889--Correspondence.; Garfield, James A. (James Abram), 1831-1881--Correspondence.; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885--Correspondence.; Harlan, John Marshall, 1833-1911--Correspondence.; Hawes, Albert Gallatin, 1804-1849--Correspondence.; Hay, John, 1838-1905--Correspondence.; Hitchcock, Ethan Allen, 1798-1870--Correspondence.; Holt family--Correspondence.; Holt, Joseph, 1807-1894.; Holt, Margaret Wickliffe, 1821-1860--Correspondence.; Holt, Mary Harrison, 1811-1846--Correspondence.; Holt, Samuel P.--Correspondence.; Holt, Thomas H.--Correspondence.; Johnson, Reverdy, 1796-1876--Correspondence.; Johnston, Harriet Lane, 1830-1903--Correspondence.; King, Horatio, 1811-1897--Correspondence.; Lieber, Francis, 1800-1872--Correspondence.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865--Assassination.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865--Correspondence.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865--Inaugurations.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; Nicolay, John G. (John George), 1832-1901--Correspondence.; Noircy, Amelie L. de--Correspondence.; Rush, Benjamin, 1811-1877--Correspondence.; Scott, Winfield, 1786-1866--Correspondence.; Sims, J. Marion (James Marion), 1813-1883--Correspondence.; Speed, James, 1812-1887--Correspondence.; Stanton, Edwin M. (Edwin McMasters), 1814-1869--Correspondence.; Surratt, Mary E. (Mary Eugenia), 1820-1865--Trials, litigation, etc.; Wallace, Lew, 1827-1905--Correspondence.; Weichmann, Louis J.--Correspondence.
Organizations
Democratic Party (U.S.); Knights of the Golden Circle.; United States. Army. Office of the Judge Advocate General.; United States. War Department.
Subjects
Elections--United States--1852.; Elections--United States--1856.; Law--Kentucky.; Law--Mississippi.; Trials (Assassination)--Washington (D.C.)
Places
Kentucky--Politics and government--1792-1865.; Mississippi--Politics and government--To 1865.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--Politics and government--19th century.
Titles
Joseph Holt Papers at the Library of Congress
Occupations
Cabinet officers.; Judges.; Lawyers.
Provenance
The papers of Joseph Holt, United States postmaster general, secretary of war, judge advocate general of the United States Army, and lawyer, were given to the Library of Congress by Mrs. Walter M. Rose in 1907. Additions were given by Joseph H. Rose in 1954-1957.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Joseph Holt are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Online Content
The papers of Joseph Holt are available on the Library of Congress Web site at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.mss/collmss.ms000068.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1807, Jan. 6 Born, Breckinridge County, Ky.
1828 Opened law office, Elizabethtown, Ky.
1832 Moved to Louisville, Ky. Assistant editor, Louisville Advertiser
1833 1835 Commonwealth’s attorney, Louisville District, Ky.
1835 1842 Practiced law, Port Gibson and Vicksburg, Miss.
1842 Returned to Louisville, Ky.
1848 1851 Toured Europe and Egypt
1852 Supported Franklin Pierce for president
1856 Supported James Buchanan for president
1857 Moved to Washington, D.C.; appointed commissioner of patents
1859 1861 Postmaster general
1861 Secretary of war
1862 1875 Judge advocate general of the army
1865 Presided over military commission to try the Abraham Lincoln assassination conspirators
1866 Published “Vindication of Judge Advocate General Holt,” Washington Chronicle
1875 Retired from the army
1888 Published article on trial of Mary Surratt, North American Review
1894, Aug. 1 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Joseph Holt (1807-1894) span the years 1797-1917, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1859-1889. The collection consists principally of correspondence supplemented by diaries, ledgers, account books, bills and receipts, briefs and other legal papers, newspaper clippings, speeches, photographs, and printed matter. The collection is organized into seven series: General Correspondence and Related Material; Personal Correspondence, Winfield Scott Correspondence; Diaries, Notebooks, and Epistolary Records; Financial Papers; Miscellany; and Oversize.
Holt’s career as newspaper editor, lawyer, local politician, cabinet member, and first judge advocate general of the United States Army is illumined by this collection. Holt’s correspondence from the 1830s and 1840s relates largely to legal matters and politics in Kentucky and Mississippi. In particular, the letters from Albert Gallatin Hawes, a United States Representative from Kentucky, afford generous glimpses into politics of that state.
The emerging sectional conflicts that ultimately led to the Civil War drew Holt into national politics. On the eve of the war he occupied a prominent place in the ranks of the Democratic Party. In 1859, he was appointed postmaster general by President James Buchanan. In January 1861, he was appointed secretary of war, an appointment he later described in an article entitled “How I Became Secretary of War.” Among Holt’s tasks as secretary of war was keeping the peace in the capital during Lincoln’s inauguration. Correspondence between Holt and Winfield Scott reflects concern over numerous rumors of planned assassination attempts by the Knights of the Golden Circle and other pro-Southern organizations.
On Sept. 3, 1862, Holt was appointed judge advocate general of the army. Though a Southerner and a Democrat, he supported the Union. The newly-created post to which he was named carried the responsibility for the establishment of military commissions with jurisdiction over civilian offenders.
On May 4, 1865, a military commission was convened to try the Abraham Lincoln assassination conspirators. The event was to color the rest of Holt’s life. The Holt Papers contain voluminous correspondence regarding the commission as well as affidavits, depositions, transcribed testimony, and various versions of the charges against the conspirators. Particularly noteworthy is the correspondence between Holt and Louis J. Weichmann, a principal government witness in the conspiracy trial. Their correspondence began in May 1865 and continued for almost thirty years. Also in the collection are items relating to allegations that Holt suppressed a clemency petition addressed to President Andrew Johnson on behalf of Mary Surratt; a seven-page letter from Mrs. Samuel Mudd to Holt, pleading her husband’s innocence; Holt’s correspondence with other members of the commission after the trial; and a draft of the charges against the conspirators in the handwriting of Secretary of War Edwin M. Stanton.
Correspondents include Jeremiah S. Black, James Buchanan, Simon Cameron, James A. Garfield, Ulysses S. Grant, John Marshall Harlan, John Hay, Ethan Allen Hitchcock, Mary Harrison Holt, Margaret Wickliffe Holt, Richard S. Holt, Samuel P. Holt, Thomas H. Holt, Reverdy Johnson, Horatio King, Harriet Lane, Francis Lieber, Abraham Lincoln, Benjamin Rush, John G. Nicolay, Amelie L. de Noircy, Winfield Scott, J. Marion Sims, James Speed, and Lew Wallace.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in seven series:
General Correspondence and Related Material, 1817-1894
Personal Correspondence, 1832-1895
Winfield Scott Correspondence, 1861
Diaries, Notebooks, and Epistolary Record, 1836-1892
Financial Papers, 1822-1894
Miscellany, 1797-1917
Oversize, 1830-1850
Container List
- General Correspondence and Related Material, 1817-1894 (Box 1-97)
  Bound volumes of letters received and sent. Includes transcripts of the trial of the Abraham Lincoln assassination conspirators, drafts of the charges, transcripts of correspondence, legal miscellany, speeches to the juries, and other miscellaneous items.
  Arranged and bound chronologically, with some items filed out of order.
  - 1817, Mar. 7 -1830, Aug. 5 (Box 1)
  - 1830, Aug. 6 -1832, Nov. 13 (Box 2)
  - 1832, Nov. 14 -1834, Apr. 2 (Box 3)
  - 1834, Apr. 3 -1835, Feb. 16 (Box 4)
  - 1835, Feb. 17 -1836, Oct. 19 (Box 5)
  - 1836, Oct. 20 -1838, Mar. 26 (Box 6)
  - 1838, Mar. 27 -1840, Apr. 11 (Box 7)
  - 1840, Apr. 12 -1841, June 30 (Box 8)
  - 1841, July 1 -1843, Mar. 29 (Box 9)
  - 1843, Mar. 30 -1845, Jan. 15 (Box 10)
  - 1845, Jan. 16 -1846, Feb. 14 (Box 11)
  - 1846, Feb. 15 -1848, Feb. 29 (Box 12)
  - 1848, Mar. 1 -1851, Mar. 5 (Box 13)
  - 1851, Mar. 6 -1852, June 24 (Box 14)
  - 1852, June 25 -1853, Oct. 25 (Box 15)
  - 1853, Oct. 26 -1856, Apr. 17 (Box 16)
  - 1856, Apr. 18 -1857, Nov. 26 (Box 17)
  - 1857, Nov. 27 -1858, Oct. 7 (Box 18)
  - 1858, Oct. 8 -1859, Mar. 18 (Box 19)
  - 1859, Mar. 19-June 13 (Box 20)
  - 1859, June 14-Nov. 14 (Box 21)
  - 1859, Nov. 15 -1860, Jan. 5 (Box 22)
  - 1860, Jan. 6-Feb. 23 (Box 23)
  - 1860, Feb. 24-June 12 (Box 24)
  - 1860, June 13-Nov. 13 (Box 25)
  - 1860, Nov. 14 -1861, Jan. 25 (Box 26)
  - 1861, Jan. 26-Feb. 28 (Box 27)
  - 1861, Mar. 1-June 9 (Box 28)
  - 1861, June 10-Sept. 2 (Box 29)
  - 1861, Sept. 3-Oct. 22 (Box 30)
  - 1861, Oct. 23 -Dec. 31, undated (Box 31)
  - 1862, Jan. 1-Apr. 4 (Box 32)
  - 1862, Apr. 5-July 3 (Box 33)
  - 1862, July 4-Oct. 11 (Box 34)
  - 1862, Oct. 12-Dec. 10 (Box 35)
  - 1862, Dec. 11 -1863, Feb. 7 (Box 36)
  - 1863, Feb. 8-Mar. 16 (Box 37)
  - 1863, Mar. 17-May 31 (Box 38)
  - 1863, June 1-Aug. 24 (Box 39)
  - 1863, Aug. 25-Nov. 13 (Box 40)
  - 1863, Nov. 14 -1864, Jan. 6 (Box 41)
  - 1864, Jan. 7-Feb. 29 (Box 42)
  - 1864, Mar. 1-June 18 (Box 43)
  - 1864, June 19-Sept. 27 (Box 44)
  - 1864, Sept. 28-Dec. 9 (Box 45)
  - 1864, Dec. 10-1865, Mar. 11 (Box 46)
  - 1865, Mar. 12-May 22 (Box 47)
  - 1865, May 23-July 8 (Box 48)
  - 1865, July 9-Sept. 16 (Box 49)
  - 1865, Sept. 17-Dec.20 (Box 50)
  - 1865, Dec. 21 -1866, Apr. 5 (Box 51)
  - 1866, Apr. 6-July 26 (Box 52)
  - 1866, July 27-Sept. 28 (Box 53)
  - 1866, Sept. 29-Dec. 26 (Box 54)
  - 1866, Dec. 27-1867, Apr. 3 (Box 55)
  - 1867, Apr. 4-July 17 (Box 56)
  - 1867, July 18-Dec. 23 (Box 57)
  - 1867, Dec. 24-1868, May 4 (Box 58)
  - 1868, May 5-Oct. 31 (Box 59)
  - 1868, Nov. 1-1869, Mar. 11 (Box 60)
  - 1869, Mar. 12-Aug. 22 (Box 61)
  - 1869, Aug. 23-1870, Feb. 24 (Box 62)
  - 1870, Feb. 25-1871, Jan. 5 (Box 63)
  - 1871, Jan. 6-1872, Jan. 8 (Box 64)
  - 1872, Jan. 9 -1872, Oct. 28 (Box 65)
  - 1872. Oct. 29-1873, July 21 (Box 66)
  - 1873, July 22-Dec. 23 (Box 67)
  - 1873, Dec. 24 -1874, Sept. 30 (Box 68)
  - 1874, Oct. 1-1875, July 15 (Box 69)
  - 1875, July 16 -1876, June 15 (Box 70)
  - 1876, June 16 -1877, July 4 (Box 71)
  - 1877, July 5 -1879, July 6 (Box 72)
  - 1879, July 7 -1881, May 11 (Box 73)
  - 1881, May 12-1882, July 20 (Box 74)
  - 1882, July 21-1883, Sept. 24 (Box 75)
  - 1883, Sept. 25 -1884, May 15 (Box 76)
  - 1884, May 16 -1885, May 28 (Box 77)
  - 1885, May 29 -1886, Jan. 26 (Box 78)
  - 1886, Jan. 27 -1887, Jan. 19 (Box 79)
  - 1887, Jan. 20-Oct. 9 (Box 80)
  - 1887, Oct. 10-1888, Feb. 7 (Box 81)
  - 1888, Feb. 8-June 7 (Box 82)
  - 1888, June 8-Nov. 15 (Box 83)
  - 1888, Nov. 16-1889, Mar. 13 (Box 84)
  - 1889, Mar. 14-Aug. 6 (Box 85)
  - 1889, Aug. 7-Dec. 26 (Box 86)
  - 1889, Dec. 27-1890, June 20 (Box 87)
  - 1890, June 21 -1891, Jan. 15 (Box 88)
  - 1891, Jan. 16-Sept. 22 (Box 89)
  - 1891, Sept. 23 -1892, Nov. 22 (Box 90)
  - 1892, Nov. 23 -1894, Aug. 2 (Box 91)
  - Trial of Abraham Lincoln conspirators (transcripts of depositions, drafts of charges, transcripts of correspondence, and miscellany), (1 vol.) (Box 92)
  - Trial of Abraham Lincoln conspirators (transcripts of depositions, drafts of charges, transcripts of correspondence, and miscellany), (1 vol.) (Box 93)
  - Legal miscellany (Box 94)
    - Communications to newspapers (Box 94)
    - Speeches to juries (Box 95)
  - School exercises, college speeches, and Lyman mandamus papers See also Oversize (Box 96)
  - Owen, Irish, and Gooch case, Jacob Thompson charges (Box 97)
- Personal Correspondence, 1832-1895 (Box 98-101)
  Mainly correspondence with family members and friends.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1832-1838 (Box 98)
  - 1839 (Box 98)
  - 1840-1841 (Box 98)
  - 1842-1844 (Box 98)
  - 1845-1849 (Box 98)
  - 1850-1853 (Box 98)
  - 1854-1857 (Box 98)
  - 1858 (Box 98)
  - 1859, Jan.-Apr. (Box 99)
  - 1859, May-July (Box 99)
  - 1859, Aug.-Sept. (Box 99)
  - 1859, Oct.-Nov. (Box 99)
  - 1859, Dec., undated (Box 99)
  - 1860, Jan. (Box 99)
  - 1860, Feb. (Box 99)
  - 1860, Mar.-Dec. (Box 99)
  - 1861 (Box 99)
  - 1862-1865 (Box 99)
  - 1866 (Box 99)
  - 1867-1869 (Box 100)
  - 1870-1873 (Box 100)
  - 1874-1875 (Box 100)
  - 1876-1877 (Box 100)
  - 1878-1879 (Box 100)
  - 1880-1882 (Box 100)
  - 1883 (Box 100)
  - 1884-1885 (Box 100)
  - 1886-1887 (Box 100)
  - 1888-1889 (Box 100)
  - 1890 (Box 100)
  - 1891-1893 (Box 100)
  - 1894-1895 (Box 101)
  - Undated (1 of 2) (Box 101)
  - Undated (2 of 2) (Box 101)
  - Correspondence from friends, in French, undated (1 of 3) (Box 101)
  - Correspondence from friends, in French, undated (2 of 3) (Box 101)
  - Correspondence from friends, in French, undated (3 of 3) (Box 101)
  - Correspondence with family, undated (Box 101)
- Winfield Scott Correspondence, 1860-1861, 1907 (Box 101)
  Letters between Holt and Scott.
  - 1860-1861, 1907 (Box 101)
- Diaries, Notebooks, and Epistolary Record, 1836-1892 (Box 102)
  Diaries, notebooks, and epistolary record.
  Organized into three groupings and arranged chronologically.
  - Diaries (Box 102)
    - 1842, 1849?
    - 1849 (Box 102)
    - 1850 (Box 102)
    - 1855, with flyleaf inscribed "Wm. G. McAdoo, Knoxville, Tennessee" (Box 102)
    - 1869 (Box 102)
    - Undated (Box 102)
  - Notebooks (Box 102)
    - 1836-1837, 1852, circa 1855 (Box 102)
    - 1887-1892, undated (Box 102)
  - Epistolary record, 1853-1883 (Box 102)
- Financial Papers, 1822-1894 (Box 103-113)
  Canceled checkbook, ledgers, account books, bills and receipts, and indenture.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Completed checkbook with check stubs, 1871-1875 (Box 103)
  - Ledgers
    - Chilton & Reily, 1834-1837; Holt & Chilton, 1835-1840 (Box 103)
    - Family expenditures, 1842-1843 (Box 103)
  - Account books (Box 103)
    - 1836-1838 (Box 103)
    - 1837, (2 vols.) (Box 103)
    - 1837-1839 (Box 103)
    - 1839-1845, 1842-1844, 1843-1844 (Box 103)
    - 1844-1845 (2 vols), 1845-1846, 1846 (Box 104)
    - 1846-1847, 1846-1848, 1847-1848 (Box 104)
    - 1848-1849 (Box 104)
    - 1849-1850, 1850-1851, 1851-1852 (Box 104)
    - 1852, 1853-1854, 1854 (Box 104)
    - 1855-1859, 1860, 1862 (Box 104)
    - 1864-1866 (Box 104)
    - 1866-1875, 1867-1869 (Box 104)
    - 1869-1871, 1872-1878, 1876-1877 (Box 104)
    - 1878-1887, 1879-1884 (includes two pages from 1857), 1880-1881 (Box 104)
    - 1882, 1883, 1884-1889 (Box 105)
    - Undated (Box 105)
  - Bills and receipts (Box 105)
    - 1822-1830 (Box 105)
    - 1831-1833 (Box 105)
    - 1834 (Box 105)
    - 1835-1836 (Box 105)
    - 1837 (Box 105)
    - 1838 (Box 105)
    - 1839 (Box 105)
    - 1840 (Box 105)
    - 1841 (Box 105)
    - 1842 (Box 106)
    - 1843 (Box 106)
    - 1844 (Box 106)
    - 1845 (Box 106)
    - 1846 See also Oversize (Box 106)
    - 1847 (Box 106)
    - 1848 (Box 106)
    - 1849 (Box 106)
    - 1850 (Box 106)
    - 1851 (Box 106)
    - 1852 (Box 106)
    - 1853 (Box 106)
    - 1854-1856 (Box 107)
    - 1857 (Box 107)
    - 1858 (Box 107)
    - 1859 (1 of 2) (Box 107)
    - 1859 (2 of 2) (Box 107)
    - 1860 (Box 107)
    - 1861 (Box 107)
    - 1862 (Box 107)
    - 1863 (Box 107)
    - 1864 (Box 108)
    - 1865 (Box 108)
    - 1866 (Box 108)
    - 1867 (Box 108)
    - 1868 (Box 108)
    - 1869 (Box 108)
    - 1870 (1 of 2) (Box 109)
    - 1870 (2 of 2) (Box 109)
    - 1871 (Box 109)
    - 1872 (1 of 2) (Box 109)
    - 1872 (2 of 2) (Box 109)
    - 1873 (Box 109)
    - 1874 (1 of 2) (Box 109)
    - 1874 (2 of 2) (Box 109)
    - 1875 (Box 110)
    - 1876 (1 of 2) (Box 110)
    - 1876 (2 of 2) (Box 110)
    - 1877 (1 of 2) (Box 110)
    - 1877 (2 of 2) (Box 110)
    - 1878 (1 of 2) (Box 110)
    - 1878 (2 of 2) (Box 110)
    - 1879 (1 of 2) (Box 111)
    - 1879 (2 of 2) (Box 111)
    - 1880 (Box 111)
    - 1881 (Box 111)
    - 1882 (1 of 2) (Box 111)
    - 1882 (2 of 2) (Box 111)
    - 1883 (1 of 2) (Box 111)
    - 1883 (2 of 2) (Box 111)
    - 1884 (Box 112)
    - 1885 (Box 112)
    - 1886 (Box 112)
    - 1887 (Box 112)
    - 1888 (Box 112)
    - 1889 (Box 112)
    - 1890 (Box 112)
    - 1891 (Box 113)
    - 1892 (Box 113)
    - 1893 (1 of 2) (Box 113)
    - 1893 (2 of 2) (Box 113)
    - 1894-1896 (Box 113)
    - Undated (Box 113)
      - 1 of 6 (Box 113)
      - 2 of 6 See also Oversize (Box 113)
      - 3 of 6 (Box 113)
      - 4 of 6 (Box 113)
      - 5 of 6 (Box 114)
      - 6 of 6 (Box 114)
  - Indenture, Oct. 1841 (Box 114)
- Miscellany, 1797-1917 (Box 114-118)
  Invitations, acceptances, calling cards, legal notes, a French copybook, roll book, passport, clippings, photographs, printed matter, an article by Holt, editorial remarks, an autobiography of Holt, and scrapbooks.
  - Article, "How I Became Secretary of War," undated (Box 114)
  - Autobiography, undated (Box 114)
  - Clippings, 1830-1917, undated (Box 114)
    - 1 of 3 (Box 114)
    - 2 of 3 (Box 114)
    - 3 of 3 (Box 114)
  - Editorial remarks from the Louisville Journal, 1852, Mar. 6 (Box 114)
  - Invitations, acceptances, and calling cards (Box 114)
    - 1852, 1857-1870 (Box 114)
    - 1871-1880 (Box 114)
    - 1881-1892, 1900-1904 (Box 115)
    - Undated, arranged alphabetically by name of sender (Box 115)
      - A-B (Box 115)
      - C-D (Box 115)
      - E-F (Box 115)
      - G-H (Box 115)
      - I-L (Box 115)
      - M-N (Box 115)
      - O-R (Box 115)
      - S (Box 116)
      - T-Y (Box 116)
      - Other (Box 116)
  - Legal notes (Box 116)
    - Bound, 1826-1830, undated (Box 116)
    - Unbound (Box 116)
      - 1797, 1823-1830 (Box 116)
      - 1831-1838, 1847 (Box 116)
      - Undated (Box 116)
  - Manuscript copybook, in French, 1848-1849 (Box 116)
  - Map, La Crescent, Houston Co., Minn., 1850 See also Oversize (Box 116)
  - Military pass, 1863 (Box 116)
  - Passports, 1842, 1849-1850 (Box 117)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 117)
  - Printed matter (Box 117)
    - Business cards (Box 117)
    - General (Box 117)
      - 1830-1850s See also Oversize (Box 117)
      - 1861-1877 See also Oversize (Box 117)
      - 1880-1889 (Box 117)
      - 1890-1894 (Box 117)
      - Undated (Box 117)
        - 1 of 2 See also Oversize (Box 117)
        - 2 of 2 (Box 117)
    - Holt, Joseph, Brief and Argument in the High Court of Errors and Appeals, in the case of Jane B. Ross, et al. vs. Daniel Vertner, et al., January Term, 1840 (Jackson: Office of the "Mississippian," 1840) (Box 118)
    - International Exhibition, Philadelphia, Pa., 1876 (Box 118)
    - Roll book, undated (Box 118)
    - School exercise books (Box 118)
      - 1823-1827 (Box 118)
      - Undated (Box 118)
    - Scrapbooks (Box 118)
      - 1859-1863 (Box 118)
      - 1859-1888 (Box 118)
- Oversize, 1830-1850 (Box OV 1-OV 3)
  Maps, financial papers, newspapers, and printed matter.
  Arranged and described according to the series, container, and folder from which the items were removed.
  - General correspondence and related material (Box OV 1)
    - Map, “Township 12 Range 2 East of Pearl River,” highlighting the tract of the representatives of John Hartley (Container 96) (Box OV 1)
  - Financial papers (Box OV 1)
    - Bills and receipts (Box OV 1)
      - Insurance policy from Lexington Fire, Life and Marine Insurance Co., Oct. 21, 1846 (Container 106) (Box OV 1)
      - Account statement, undated (Container 113) (Box OV 1)
  - Miscellany (Box OV 2)
    - Map, La Crescent, Houston Co., Minn., 1850 (Container 116) (Box OV 2)
    - Printed matter (Box OV 3)
      - General (Box OV 3)
        - 1830-1850s (Container 117, folder 4) (Box OV 3)
          - Western Tiller (Cincinnati, Ohio), May 7, 1830 (Box OV 3)
          - Hawes, Albert G., "To the Freemen of the 11th Congressional District," July 25, 1831 (Box OV 3)
          - Sentinel and Expositor (Vicksburg, Miss.), May 2, 1837 (Box OV 3)
          - Blank form, Circuit Court, State of Mississippi, circa 1830s (Box OV 3)
        - 1861-1877 (Container 117, folder 5) (Box OV 3)
          - Real Estate Journal (Washington, D.C.), vol. 1, no. 5, Dec. 1875 (Box OV 3)
          - "Schedule of Steamers appointed to convey the United States Mails to Foreign Countries during the month of August, 1876" (Box OV 3)
        - Undated (folder 1 of 2) (Box OV 3)
          - Advertisement for Harper’s Pictorial History of the Rebellion (Box OV 3)